Finding Aid for Spalding Family Papers, (microfilm) 1808-1910
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Family Papers
  - 1842
    - August 18, 1842 Joseph Addison Sexton gives a good description of Manchester, New York. (Reel 1)
    - November 7, 1842 an account of Greenport, Long Island, New York, by Joseph Addison Sexton. (Reel 1)
  - 1843
    - June 10, 1843 Henry Sexton tells of teaching in Frenchtown, New York, and compares the area to Connecticut. (Reel 2)
  - 1844
    - July 2, 1844 Henry Sexton describes school teaching in Somers, New York, and the nearby towns. (Reel 2)
  - 1845 (Reel 2)
  - January-June 1846
    - February 25, 1846 letter from sister, Mary Lively, urging Miranda Sexton to come South. Describes opening in Greene County, Alabama, school. (Reel 2)
    - April 20, 1846 letter from friend of Miranda Sexton in Brooklyn, Connecticut, praising the South. (Reel 2)
  - July-December 1846
    - August 21, 1846 friend of Miranda Sexton describes conditions in Easton, Pennsylvania, particularly the Germans. (Reel 2)
  - 1847
    - March 10, 1847 comments of Miranda Sexton on why she doesn't like Alabama. (Reel 2)
  - 1848
    - December 10, 1848 Alfred Sexton tells how Sexton relatives are doing in Alabama. (Reel 2)
  - 1849
    - July 2, 1849 John Sexton comments on Southern love of gaiety and social pleasure. (Reel 2)
  - 1850-1851
    - July 26, 1850 William Spalding writes his wife of social activities at the Soo, particularly the fraternization with the British. (Reel 2)
    - September, 8 1850 William Spalding describes business developments at the Soo. (Reel 2)
    - July 30, 1851 Ann Gray Sexton tells of events (Arkansas fever, hard times) and personages (friends and relatives) in Alabama. (Reel 2)
    - October 14, 1851 Otis Sexton tells about Apalachicola, Florida, and his congregation there. (Reel 2)
  - 1852
    - February 19, 1852 from Mary Spalding describing hard times in New Lisbon, Ohio -the bank failure -mention of the Hanna family(Dr. Leonard Hanna, father of Mark) planning to move to Cleveland. (Reel 2)
    - May 29, 1852-Mary Spalding relates experiences in Madison, Indiana, including a visit to a German-speaking Lutheran church. (Reel 2)
    - December 15, 1852 Mary Sexton Lively describes voyage from New York to New Orleans. (Reel 2)
  - 1853-1854
    - December 13, 1853 John Sexton comments on the Chinese whom the missionary brought to Alabama and the parsimony of Alabama planters in religious contributions. (Reel 2)
  - 1855-1856
    - August 29, 1855 John Sexton discusses the advantages of being a land owner or manufacturer over being a merchant and relates the experiences of the Sexton family in commerce. (Reel 2)
    - December 1855 Mary Spalding comments on religion and spiritualism. (Reel 2)
    - May 8, 1856 letter from Mary Sexton Lively in Texas describing conditions there. (Reel 2)
    - September 25, and October 4, 1856 from William Spalding on the development of Bayfield, Wisconsin. (Reel 2)
    - November 27, 1856 friend of William Spalding describes trip to California via the Isthmus and comments on the San Jose, California, area. (Reel 2)
    - November 28, 1856 Mary Spalding Chamberlain comments on the mental institution in which mother Spalding has been placed. (Reel 2)
  - 1857-1859
    - February 18, 1857 William Spalding tells of his travels through the Upper Peninsula of Michigan and life in Marquette, Michigan. (Reel 3)
    - September 15, 1858 more from Mary Sexton Lively on life in Texas, including work with Chism. (Reel 3)
    - May 12, 1859 Ann Gray Sexton on the problems of planting in Alabama; debts. (Reel 3)
    - December 4, 1859 Mary Sexton Lively comments on the cattle business of Chism and the troubles on the Texas border. (Reel 3)
  - 1860
    - June 21, 1860, April 28, 1861 Mary Sexton Lively tells more about Texas and life there. (Reel 3)
  - January-May 1861
    - April 6, 1861 William Spalding comments on war fever in New York and on Henry Ward Beecher. (Reel 3)
  - June-December 1861 (Reel 3)
  - January-September 1862
    - April 4, 1862 description of Westfield, Wisconsin a new arrival, a friend of William Spalding. (Reel 3)
    - September 17, 1862 William Spalding's employee, R.C. Kibby, describes business and politics at the Soo. (Reel 3)
    - September 21, 1862 William Spalding recounts conditions in the army and comments on the "secesh" at the Soo. (Reel 3)
  - October-December 1862 (Reel 3)
  - January-March 1863
    - March 20 April 26, 1863 from brother, John Sexton, to Miranda Spalding describing capture by the Union army, desire to be released, and news of the Sexton family in Alabama. (Reel 3)
  - April-June 1863
    - May 14, 1863 from brother John Sexton continuing correspondence of March and April (Reel 3)
    - June 12, 1863 from Edwin Sexton, in the Union army, telling of brother John's service in the Rebel army and his capture. (Reel 3)
  - July-September 1863
    - July 9, 1863 business, personal, and political affairs at the Soo, from Kibby. (Reel 4)
    - August 25, 1863 papers on the history of the 27th Michigan Infantry, including the dissension in the regiment and the condemnation of Col. Fox. (Reel 4)
    - September 9, 1863 from Thomas S. Sprague, formerly with the regiment: Saginaw is booming, lots of opportunities there. (Reel 4)
    - September 26, 1863 William Spalding's description of the Tennessee campaign -people, terrain, and marches. (Reel 4)
  - October-December 1863
    - November 12, 1863 William Spalding's account of the fighting in East Tennessee. (Reel 4)
    - November 14, 1863 letter from former member of the regiment, J.R. Richardson, in Tuscola County, Michigan, describing problems of raising men and the draft and the good business conditions. (Reel 4)
    - December 13, 1863 Mary Spalding Chamberlain comments on Blacks in Canisteo, New York. (Reel 4)
  - January-February 1864
    - January 2, 1864 brother John Spalding in Cleveland comments about silver mining in the Upper Peninsula and business opportunities in Marquette. (Reel 4)
    - February 21, 1864 from Kibby about events at the Soo. (Reel 4)
  - March-June 1864
    - March 17, 1864 from Richardson: news of former members of the regiment and conditions in Tuscola. (Reel 4)
    - March 20, 1864 more from Kibby on doings at the Soo. (Reel 4)
    - April 7, 1864 William Spalding comments on the problem of deserters and secessionist sentiment in Baltimore, Maryland, through which his regiment passed. (Reel 4)
    - April 10, 1864 Edwin Sexton sends copy of letter from nephew, Charles S. Lively, recently arrived at father's relatives in Illinois, which describes hard conditions in Texas during the war. (Reel 4)
    - April 20, 1864 William Spalding's resignation from the 27th Michigan is accepted. (Reel 4)
    - May 10, 1864 more news on Texas from Mary Sexton Lively. (Reel 4)
  - July-September 1864
    - July 27 (resumed August 13) 1864 from William Childs: Black troops and their behavior in the battle of the crater before Petersburg. (Reel 4)
    - July 28, 1864 Mary Sexton Lively gives detailed account of conditions in Texas and the impact of slavery on non-slaveholders. (Reel 4)
    - August 15, 1864 from William Childs: discussing Lake Superior mining rush (gold and silver) and action before Petersburg and expressing the hope that Spalding will not be drafted. (Reel 4)
    - August 19, 1864 from Richardson: in Tuscola, the problems of the draft, particularly for those who have already served. (Reel 4)
    - August 21, 1864 Mary Sexton Lively again dwells on the effects of the war in Texas. (Reel 4)
    - August 29, 1864 from B.C. Sweet discussing mining in Marquette and the prices for miners. (Reel 4)
  - October-December 1864
    - November 11, 1864 Daniel G. Cash, a member of Spalding's regiment comments on his experiences as a Confederate prisoner. (Reel 4)
  - 1865-1866
    - December 2, 1866 from Mary Sexton Lively describing her miserable life in Texas trying to raise cotton during the war. (Reel 4)
  - 1867-1869
    - June 4, 1869 nephew, Charles S. Lively, describes Illinois and conditions in his family (Reel 4)
  - 1870-1879
    - January 24, 1870 Mary Sexton Lively discusses her recent return to Texas and the miserable life there. (Reel 4)
    - September 6, 1872 John Sexton recounts the impact of the war on Alabama planters and the failure of merchants, such as brother Alfred, who tried planting. (Reel 4)
    - August 2, 1873 John Sexton, ex-Confederate soldier, discusses how the war divided the Sexton family. (Reel 4)
    - October 31, 1880 William Spalding, Jr. describes political developments in North Carolina. (Reel 4)
    - December 3, 1881 Miranda Sexton Spalding comments on Sault Ste. Marie, Michigan, past and present. (Reel 4)
  - 1880-1887 (Reel 5)
  - 1888-1889 (Reel 5)
  - 1890 (Reel 5)
  - 1891-June 1892 (Reel 5)
  - July 1892-1895 (Reel 5)
  - 1896 (Reel 5)
  - 1897 (Reel 5)
  - 1898-1899 (Reel 5)
  - 1900-1901 (Reel 6)
    (includes letter 1901 from Adele Spalding concerning mining in the West)
  - 1902 (Reel 6)
  - 1903 (Reel 6)
  - 1904 (Reel 6)
    (Edward Spalding tells of his trip to England, August 28, 1904)
  - 1905-1906 (Reel 6)
  - 1907-1908 (Reel 6)
  - 1909 (Reel 6)
  - 1910 (Reel 6)
- Other materials
  - Reminiscences of William P. Spalding (1822- ) undated (Reel 6)
  - Miscellanea (Reel 6)
  - Miscellaneous newspaper clippings with material on the Spalding family (Reel 6)
  - Photo album cover with Indian on the cover (Reel 6)
  - Photograph album, largely of Upper Peninsula life and customs, undated (Reel 6)
  - Photographs (Reel 6)
- Family materials 1837-1890
  (addition of November 1, 1979)
  - 1837-1845 (Reel 7)
    - February 19, 1837-Mary Sexton Lively's impressions of New Orleans, Louisiana. (Reel 7)
    - December 12, 1839-William Hill, friend of the Rev. Joseph Addison Sexton, gives his opinions on slavery, abolitionists, and Presbyterian church divisions in the Great Valley of Virginia. (Reel 7)
  - 1846-1847 (Reel 7)
    (Correspondence of the Rev. Joseph Addison Sexton while serving as a Presbyterian minister in New River, Louisiana, from fellow clergy and relatives on developments in the church in New Orleans, Louisiana, Port Gibson, Mississippi, and Canton, Connecticut, and to and from him on family matters, especially the possibility of his sister Miranda moving South.)
    - March 23, 1846-Alfred Sexton of Alabama to his sister, Miranda, disparaging marriageable men and attitudes toward school teachers in the South. (Reel 7)
    - March 30, 1846-Joseph Addison Sexton of Louisiana to his sister, Miranda, advising her not to come South. (Reel 7)
    - December 13, 1847-Joseph Addison Sexton on dental fees and opportunities in the area of New River, Louisiana. (Reel 7)
  - 1850-1859 (especially 1850) (Reel 7)
    (Correspondence from William Spalding, a dealer in general merchandise and mining supplies based at the Soo, to his wife, Miranda Sexton Spalding, on his business activities, including buying and selling trips.)
    - April 23, 1852-Joseph Addison Sexton on advantages of homeopathic over allopathic medicine. (Reel 7)
    - October 7, 1852-Miranda Sexton Spalding on method of treatment for burns suffered by son Genie. (Reel 7)
    - September 30, 1853-Mary Sexton Lively on the economy of Gonzales, Texas, and child birthing. (Reel 7)
    - October 11, 1853-William Spalding on economic and social conditions at the Soo. (Reel 7)
    - April 6, 1856-William Spalding on his overland trip from the Soo to the Straits of Mackinac. (Reel 7)
  - June 1862-August 1863 (Reel 7)
    (Correspondence from William Spalding, Quartermaster of the 27th Michigan Infantry, to his wife, Miranda Sexton Spalding, on organizing the regiment (procuring men, equipment, provisions, etc.), the move South, his illness and confinement in a Louisville, Kentucky, military hospital.)
  - 1864-1890 (scattered) (Reel 7)